CINDY LAO

SUMMARY

I am Cindy, a User Researcher with a background in tourism. Throughout my career, I have worked in close contact with the consumer which has developed my user research skills and empathy. My process is heavily focused on discovery and early validation to deliver value to the user and measurable results for the business.

KEY SKILLS

- User Research
- Sketching/Wireframing
- Information Architecture User Interface Design
- Responsive web design
- Prototyping
- Usability Testing
- Heuristic analysis

TOOLS

- Figma, Adobe XD
- Invision, Miro
- HTML, CSS, Javascript, Bootstrap & JQuery

UX/UI PROJECTS

The Australian Royal Navy

The aim of this project was to improve the experience on the Australian Royal Navy website and make the information more accessible to the user.

Skills used: User Research & Analysis, Persona Creation, Sketches & Wireframes, Information Architecture, Style Tile, Usability Testing, Prototyping.

Tools used: Adobe XD, Miro, Invision

The Australian Pet Welfare Foundation

The Australian Pet Welfare Foundation is an Australian non-profit organisation which provides information to key stakeholders in government, welfare agencies, veterinary professionals as well as the community about how to save lives in shelters and pounds through changed policy and legislation.

Skills used: User Experience Design (UX/UI), Heuristic Evaluation, Information Architecture, Sketches & Wireframes, Usability Testing, Prototyping.

Tools used: Figma, Miro, Google Form

Reelii App

Reelii is an app designed to help users decide on what to watch to make the most of their free time.

Skills used: User Research (Interviews + Surveys) & Analysis, Persona Creation, Competitor Analysis, Sketches & Wireframes, User Testing, User Flow, Prototyping.

Tools used: Figma, Miro, Survey Monkey

EMPLOYMENT

Travel & Operations Consultant

Abercrombie & Kent, Melbourne Nov 2017 - Present

Abercrombie & Kent is a luxury inbound tour operator offering tailor made travels. My tasks consist of actively and consistently selling to achieve individual and team sales targets. To achieve this, I need to liaise with the clients or agents to qualify the travellers' needs and expectations. I am also in charge developing relationships with key agents.

Travel Advisor

Travelbird, Amsterdam Jan 2017 - Oct 2017

Travelbird is an online travel agency startup based in Amsterdam. I delivered high-quality support and service, assisted with enquiries and issues from customers, travel agents, tour operators and hotels; and managed the social media account. I was also in charge of a new customer care project where user experience was key.

Senior Reservation Consultant

ATS Pacific, Sydney Apr 2015 - Dec 2016 I was managing the European clients portfolio to quote bookings and prices, designing clients' itineraries to and specifications, and confirming bookings. Promptly responding to customer feedback and showing initiative to address customer enquiries.

ESTL Paris (France)

EDUCATION

Melbourne

Certificate UX/UI Designer Monash University, Melbourne	11/2020 - 04/2021	Bachelor Degree in Tourism Cergy Pontoise University, (France)	09/2009 - 09/2010
Short Course UX/UI Design RMIT University,	04/2020 -	Advanced Diploma	09/2007 -
	07/2020	Tourism	06/2009